Luc T. Nguyen

South Jordan, UT 84095 (801) 915-7316 | luc_nguyen@outlook.com

OPERATIONS MANAGER/PROJECT MANAGER

Driving Business Efficiency | Results Oriented

Driving cross functional operations efficiency through communications and values clarity. Ability to achieve positive results in demanding environments and challenging situations.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Well-developed professional with extensive operations management and organizational leadership experience. Proficient at training and supervising staff, recommending solutions for processes improvement, and implementing effective programs to streamline operations. Consistently assessing operational needs to impact performance and improve efficiency, bringing 5+ years of related experience and key strengths as follows:

- Project Management
- Engaged Leadership
- Communications Clarity
- Negotiation
- Conflict Resolution
- Strategic Planning

- Operations Efficiency
- Risk Management
- Resource Management
- Process Improvement
- Cost Control
- Budget Generation/Adherence
- Multi-Functional Team Collaboration
- Team Building/Development
- Training/Supervision
- Performance Evaluation

CORE COMPETENCIES

- ✓ Consistently recognized, top-performing professional with the ability to quickly adapt and excel in new environments with experience in: technology, semi-conductors, finance, retail, and customer service.
- ✓ Leverages natural leadership and relationship building skills to increase efficiency and productivity.
- ✓ Utilize exceptional consultative listening skills combined with work experience and expertise in helping businesses improve their organizational performance.
- ✓ Determine organizational needs, propose learning solutions, and assess impact of solutions using strong analytical and problem solving skills.
- ✓ Strong work ethic and track record of success with a history of developing talent and long-lasting relationships based on a foundation of trust, integrity, and outstanding performance.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Progressive Insurance · Midvale, UT

Licensed Bodily Injury Claims Adjuster

2019 – Present

- Analyze information gathered through investigation, report findings, and interviews to determine the extent of liability and settle unrepresented bodily injury claims.
- Negotiates injury settlements based on facts of loss, mechanism of injury, extent of injuries, and other personal factors
- Interprets policies and analyzes information gathered to determine courses of action and coverage.
- Establish and maintain high level of positive working relationships with internal and external customers, ensuring satisfaction with company services.
- Calculates benefit payments and approves payment of claims within a defined monetary limit.
- Completed short term assignment with Catastrophe Team to assist with resolving high volume weather claims.
- Completed short term assignment as Total Loss Captain to assist multiple states as primary paperwork admin handler, and established documented process/role.

Amazon · Salt Lake City, UT

2018 - 2019

Manager II, Operations

• Coordinate with the Transportation Operations Management team and trucking carriers to ensure scheduling accuracy, trailer inventory, and on time trailer departures.

Luc T. Nguyen Page 2

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

- Connected with truck carriers to secure additional capacity based on inventory levels and trailer utilization.
- Collaborated with Central Flow team to forecast and manage labor plans according to predicted charge and planned volume outputs.
- Created a Learning Curve Calculator and standardized TAKT audits during Peak 2018 to track rates by each associate level which lead to a weekly average increase from 165.95 units per hour to 192.73 units per hour.
- Implemented and trained all managers on the Proactive Outbound Problem-Solving application during the launch of SLC1.
- Developed 12 Tier 1 associates into Learning Ambassadors and 4 Tier 1 associates into Tier 3 Process Assistants.
- Chairman of the Associate Safety Committee that lead associate engagements in order to mitigate work injuries and promote safety awareness.
- Managed over 50 associates on a daily basis and over 100 associates during peak operations.

IM FLASH Technologies · Lehi, UT

2015 - 2018

Manufacturing Engineering Process Supervisor

- Managed and developed 10 team members by holding 1:1 meetings, creating career development goals, finding improvement project opportunities, and provide coaching.
- Lead daily area meetings to discuss constraints, priorities, and performance metrics.
- Created Process Restriction Management loading plans to balance workstation throughput and reduce cycle time.
- Lead Manual Lot Disposition project to reduce quality risk and minimize product scrap.
- Created shift game plan to identify and communicate priorities to all teams area wide.
- Created 2 new manufacturing roles, set up expectations, and defined task responsibilities.
- Performed process value stream mapping to increase technician task efficiency by eliminating non-value added steps.

IM FLASH Technologies · Lehi, UT

2014

Photolithography Summer Intern

- Gathered and analyzed data from multiple databases to create charts and spreadsheets in order to determine capacity/utilization on manufacturing tools.
- Created weekly performance updates for engineers to optimize processing recipes.
- Analyzed and proposed a solution to automate an inspection step in the manufacturing process in order to free up 2 team members per week to perform other tasks.
- Met with multiple departments to communicate proposed changes and promote new ideas such as changing processing sequence, and removing tools to free up additional fab space.

Cyprus Credit Union: Salt Lake City, UT

2012 - 2014

Financial Service Representative

- Processed and maintained financial transactions for members.
- Created and audited new accounts.
- Provided financial services to members such as opening IRAs, CDs, and loans.

EDUCATION & DEVELOPMENT

University of Utah, David Eccles School of Business

Bachelor of Science, Operations Management (2015)

3.48 GPA/Dean's List - 2011, 2012, 2013, 2015

Director of Community Relations and Development - University of Utah Ethics Club

Languages: English, Vietnamese